時は戦国、乱世の時代。
からくり人の住むジパング国では群雄割拠して合戦に明け暮れ、
からくり武芸者たちも勝利と栄光を目指してしのぎを削っていた。
そしていま、からくり武芸者ナンバー１を目指す、とてつもないヒーローが誕生した！
ムサシ、見参でござるだス！
からくり剣豪伝ムサシロード
男はいつでも　世界の真ん中で
いちばん　強くなる日を
AH! AH! 夢見て
心の刃　大空にふりかざし
冒険の旅の　幕を開ける
ジパング国を　さすらう剣豪
その名　からくりびと　ムサシ
GO! FIGHT!
鍔迫り合いの音が
眩しい人生
戦い　昨日よりも　今日　強い
BUGEI! 二刀流　ムサシ
明日は　輝くぞ
鍔迫り合いの音が
眩しい人生
戦い　思い切りと　静けさと
BUGEI! 二刀流　ムサシ
みけんが　きらめいた　ムサシ！！
지금 막 사츠마니아에 일제 공격을 하고자 하는 시라누이 일족.
Shiranui Clan is about to do a full out attack on Satsumania.
무사시는 그걸 사이고에게 알리고자 하지만, 달아나려 하던 참에 한조에게 잡히고 만다.
Musashi tried to let Saigo know, but Hanzō caught him before he could run away.
히미코의 최면술에 걸린 무사시는 코지로 일행을 죽이라는 명령을 받고 만다.
Under the hypnotism of Himiko, Musashi was ordered to kill Kojirō and others.
시라누이 최후의
음모이오
The Last Conspiracy
of Shiranui
ここはすでに不知火の本拠地。いつ敵が襲ってくるかしれません。
油断は禁物でゴワス。
ムサシ殿！
ムサシ！無事だったよね！
시로! 뭔 일이오!
Shiro! What's wrong-gowasu?
殺せ。殺せ。
ムサシ！
ムサシ！なんてことを！
죽여라. 죽여라!
Kill. Kill!
관둬라, 무사시! 우리를 못 알아보겠냐!
Stop it, Musashi! Don't you recognize us?
무사시 군! 그만두시오!
Musashi! Stop it-gowasu!
아, 맨날 바보 취급했던 것에 화난 거라면 사과할게! 아니면 단고 못 먹게 한 거에 화난 거라면 그것도 사과할 테니까 용서해 줘!
If you're angry about being treated like a fool all the time, let us apologize!
Or if you're mad about that I didn't let you eat dangos as much as you wanted, then I'll apologize about that too!
보아하니 무사시 님은 누군가의 최면술에 걸린 것 같습니다.
It seems that Mr. Musashi is under hypnotism of some guy.
그럼 무언가 강한 충격을 가한다면...
Then, some kind of strong shock might do.
분명 눈을 뜰 것입니다.
He will wake up by doing so.
자, 와라, 무사시!
Come and face me, Musashi!
간류! 변덕의 히트!
Ganryu! Whimsy Hit!
코지로! 너 뭔 짓 한 거야!
Kojirō! What the heck did you just do!?
안심하세요. 칼등입니다.
Don't worry. I used the back of my sword.
오, 정신이 드셨소.
You're awake-gowasu!
무사시 씨!
Mr. Musashi!
뭐야, 하나도 정신 안 차렸잖아!
Hey, he didn't wake up at all!
무사시의 신경이 둔한 걸 완전히 잊어먹고 있었습니다.
I totally forgot that Musashi's nerves are insensible.
죽여라. 죽여라. 죽여라.
Kill. Kill. Kill.
체스트!
Chest!
자, 이 틈에 무사시 씨의 눈을 띄웁시다.
Let's use this chance to make Mr. Musashi wake up.
뭣이오! 왜 내가 바다에 있소!
What is it-dasu!? Why am I in sea-dasu!?
어라? 다들 모여서 하이킹 중이오?
Huh? Are you all hiking together-dasu?
뭔 무사태평한 소리 하고 있어!
Why are you so carefree!?
그랬었소. 나, 최면술에 걸렸었소.
I see-dasu. I was under hypnotism-dasu...
내게 모두를 죽이라게 하다니 히미코 놈 용서할 수 없소!
I can't forgive that Himiko as she made me try to kill everyone-dasu!
그래도, 무사시 군이 말한 대로 시라누이 일족이 사츠마니아에 공격해 들어오면 큰일이오.
But, as Musashi said, if Shiranui Clan comes to attack Satsumania, it'll be a serious problem-gowasu.
무사시 님. 시라누이 일족의 기지는 어디입니까?
Mr. Musashi. Where is Shiranui Clan's base?
내가 안내하오!
I'll guide you-dasu!
히미코 님 만세! 히미코 님 만세! 히미코 님 만세! 히미코 님 만세!
For Lord Himiko! For Lord Himiko! For Lord Himiko! For Lord Himiko!
드디어 때가 왔습니다. 규슈에 시라누이의 왕국을 만드는 것입니다.
The time finally has come. It's time to build the kingdom of Shiranui in Kyushu.
예! 히미코 여왕님 만세!
Yessir! For Lord Queen Himiko!
히미코 님. 모든 준비가 되었습니다.
Ms. Himiko. Everything is ready.
한조 님. 당신의 협력에 감사합니다.
Mr. Hanzō, thank you for your cooperation.
히미코 님에게 최후의 선물이 있습니다. 직접 보시지요.
I have a last present for you, Ms. Himiko. Please look for yourself.
한조 님, 저것은 무엇입니까.
Mr. Hanzō, what is that?
사이카이 왕국의 중심 도시, 사츠마니아에 향해 쏠 미사일입니다.
That is the missile that will hit Satsumania, the central city of the kingdom of Saikai.
사츠마니아에?
To Satsumania?
왜 그런 것을.
Why did you make such thing?
우리 군의 승리를 확실하게 하기 위함입니다. 이것 하나 있으면 지팡구 제국 전부를 수중에 넣기 쉬워집니다.
To make sure the victory of our force. That one thing will make taking the whole Jipangu into our hands easier.
그런 것을 쓰는 것은 용서할 수 없습니다.
Using a thing like that is unforgivable.
왜입니까, 히미코 님.
Why is that, Ms. Himiko?
시라누이는 사람을 죽이기 위해 전쟁을 하는 것이 아닙니다. 우리가 살 수 있는 태양이 닿는 장소만 확보할 수 있으면 됩니다.
Shiranui do not wage war to kill people. Securing the land that we can live where sun shines is all we want.
히미코 님 만세! 히미코 님 만세! 히미코 님 만세!
For Lord Himiko! For Lord Himiko! For Lord Himiko!
음, 누구냐!
Who's there!?
오, 무사시구나. 코지로 일행은 잘 처리했나?
Oh, it's you, Musashi. Did you take care of Kojirō and others?
히미코 님에게 보고를.
I have to report to Lord Himiko.
아, 그래. 자, 들어가라.
Alright. You may go in.
그렇소.
Yes.
자, 지금이오!
Now-dasu!
무기 수가 대단해!
They have so many weapons!
이게 사츠마니아에 달려들면 사츠마니아는 전멸이오.
If all of this come attack Satsumania, it'll be annihilated-gowasu.
어떻게든 조치해야...
We need to move.
내게 맡기시오!
Leave it to me-dasu!
아, 바보야, 멈춰라! 우리가 여기서 행패부려봤자 이길 리가 없잖아!
Stop it, you fool! There's no way we're going to defeat all of them by ourselves!
음, 이걸 씁시다.
Let's use these.
이 폭탄을 불을 붙이고 10분 후 폭발하게 설정되어 있습니다.
This bomb will explode 10 minutes after setting fire.
이걸 곳곳에 설치해 이 기지를 파괴하면 놈들의 계획도 물거품이 될 겁니다.
If we destroy this base by installing this to various places, their scheme will come to nothing.
역시 주베 님! 언제 그런 걸 준비했소?
You're great, Mr. Jūbee! When did you get that-dasu?
통신 판매로 주문한 것이 어제 도착하였습니다.
My mail order has arrived yesterday.
그럼 나누어져서 설치합시다.
Then let's divide and install.
누구냐!
Who's there!?
뭐야, 생쥐구나.
Oh, it's just a rat.
시로!
Shiro!
오, 여기에 설치하면 좋은 것인가.
Are you suggesting that this is a good place to install one-gowasu?
역시 시로는 착한 아이이오.
Shiro is a good boy-gowasu.
적당히 좀 하시로! 는 말도 안 되는 말장난이오.
(iikagen ni shiro! dajare, tūjinai de gowasu:
that's enough! this word play did not work so well-gowasu)
You're a bad boy! But you're not going to change-gowasu.
어? 좋은 냄새가 나오.
Something smells good-dasu.
맛있겠소!
Looks tasty-dasu!
어차피 폭발하면 없어지오! 아까우니까 내가 먹어버리겠소!
It'll end up disappearing it explodes-dasu! I'll eat instead so that these won't be wasteful-dasu!
뭘 하고 있어! 몰래 훔쳐먹을 때가 아니잖아!?
What are you doing!? This is not a time to be snitching foods!
그래도...
But...
이런 게 있으니까 안 되는 거야!
It's all because this exists!
자, 어서 폭탄 설치하자!
Now, let's keep installing bombs!
아, 알겠소.
Y- yessir-dasu.
거긴 어떠냐.
Are you done?
OK이오.
Good-dasu.
그럼 폭발하기 전에 빠져나가오.
Then let's get out before it explodes-gowasu.
출구는 이쪽이오!
The exit is on this way-dasu!
여기만 돌아가면 출구이오!
The exit is after this turn-dasu!
어라?
Huh?
바보야, 뭐가 출구냐! 여긴 시라누이의 휴게소잖아!
Hey, you idiot! This is not an exit! This is a resting room of Shiranui!
너 초 울트라급 길치구나?
You're super ultra directionally challenged!
미, 미안하오.
I- I'm sorry-dasu!
네놈들, 잘도 이 기지에 몰래 들어왔겠다. 그러나 너희에게 여기서 나갈 길은 없다.
You guys dared to come into this base, but you will have no exit.
포기하고 죽어라.
Give up and die.
체스트!
Chest!
히미코 님. 부디 출격 명령을 내려 주십시오.
Ms. Himiko. Please make an order for a sally.
에잇, 뭐라고 해도 저 미사일을 치우지 않는 한 저는 출격 명령을 내릴 수 없습니다.
No matter what you say, unless that missile is gone, I will not make such order.
그러나 그러면 우리 군에 다수의 피해가.
But that will end up leaving big damage to our forces.
여기 있는 모두는 불의 나라를 재건하기 위해서라면 다수의 희생은 각오하고 있습니다.
To revive the Fire Country, everyone here are prepared for numerous losses.
알겠습니다. 히미코 님이 말하는 대로 미사일은 처분하지요.
Understood. I will dispose the missile as you said, Ms. Himiko.
오, 그래야 한조 님. 저희을 잘 이해해 주시는군요.
That's our Mr. Hanzō. You understand us well.
그럼 전군에게 출력 명령을.
Then, please make a sortie order to all forces.
알겠습니다.
Understood.
폭발이 다가온다! 질풍노도의 후반을 기다려라!
The explosion is nearby! Wait for the stormy latter half!
카라쿠리 검호전 무사시 로드
Karakuri Kengouden: Musashi Road
시라누이 요술, 불덩어리 돌팔매!
Shiranui Magic, Fireball Throwing Stone!
체스트!
Chest!
아야야야야야야!
Ouchie!
이래선 끝이 없어. 달아나자!
There's no end to this. Let's run!
알겠습니다!
Understood!
이 틈에 달아나오!
Let's run using this moment-gowasu!
나, 히미코 씨에게 최면술을 건 답례를 하지 않으면 못 참소!
I must pay back Ms. Himiko for hypnotizing me, or I can't take this-dasu!
저, 물어볼 게 있소.
I have something to ask-dasu.
히미코 씨 방 어디이오?
Which way is Ms. Himiko's room-dasu?
아, 그거라면 저기다.
Oh, it's over there.
땡큐이오!
Thank you-dasu!
무사시!
Musashi!
뭐, 뭔 짓입니까, 한조!?
W- what are you doing, Hanzō!?
지금 여기서 병사의 수가 적어지면 내가 지팡구국을 지배하려 할 때 부하가 적어져서 말이지.
If the number of soldiers decrease here,
there won't be enough subordinates for me when I'm going to rule over Jipangu State.
한조. 그게 당신의 목적입니까.
Hanzō. Was that your true objective?
히미코. 네 병사는 내가 가져가겠다!
Himiko. I'm claiming your soldiers!
야, 히미코! 잘도 내게 최면술을 걸었겠소!
Hey, Himiko! How dare you hypnotize me-dasu!
용서할 수 없소!
That's unforgivable-dasu!
어라?
Huh?
어떻게 된 일이오?
What's going on-dasu?
무사시! 네놈 바퀴벌레처럼 끈질기게 아직도 살아 있었냐!
Musashi! You were still tenaciously alive like a cockroach!
건강하게 오래 사는 게 내 장점이오!
Being healthy and living long are my good things-dasu!
이번에야말로 저 세상에 보내 주겠다!
You're really going to the other world this time!
그건 내가 할 말이오!
That's my line-dasu!
이천일류 철풍차!
Niten'ichiryū: Iron Windmill!
네이놈, 무사시!
Musashi, how dare you!
움직이면 목이 잘린다.
Move and have your neck cut.
젠장! 비겁하오!
Damn! That's cowardly-dasu!
흥! 불만은 저 세상에 가서 늘어놓아라!
Hmph! You can list all your complaints in the other world!
으악! 나 아직 죽고 싶지 않소!
I don't want to die yet-dasu!
살려주시오, 엄마!
Help me, mother!
엄마!
Mother!
안녕이다, 무사시!
Farewell, Musashi!
눈이 뒤집혔나, 히미코!
Are you out of your mind, Himiko!?
한조.
Hanzō.
네, 네가 무사시를 죽이도록 둘 수 없습니다.
I- I can't let you kill Musashi.
무사시! 승부는 나중이다!
Musashi! We'll finish this later!
히, 히미코 씨...
M- Ms. Himiko...
히미코 씨!
Ms. Himiko!
무사시. 제가 잘못 생각하고 있었습니다. 한조는 자신의 야망만을 위해 시라누이 일족을 이용하려 하고 있었습니다.
Musashi. I was wrong. Hanzō was trying to use Shiranui Clan only for his own ambition.
무사시. 저를 용서해 주시겠습니까.
Musashi. Will you forgive me?
무, 무사시. 마지막으로 엄마라고 불러 주세요.
M- Musashi. Please call me mother for the last time.
엄마!
Mother!
막장이 되어 버렸소.
It's a dead end-gowasu.
어라? 무사시가 없어. 계속 따라오고 있다고 생각했는데.
Huh? Musashi's not here! I thought he was following us.
그 놈, 길치니까...
That guy has problems with following paths...
어쨌든 여기서 나갑시다. 이대로라면 생매장되어 버립니다.
Anyway, let's get out of here. We'll end up being buried alive at this rate.
또 나타났구나!
You appeared again!
이번에야말로 못 달아날 테다!
You're not getting away this time!
여긴 제가 상대하겠습니다. 센히메 님을 부탁합니다.
I'll face him for now. Please take care of Senhime.
알겠습니다.
Understood.
코지로, 조심해!
Kojirō, be careful!
봉황환의 힘을 보여주겠다!
I'll show you the power of Hououmaru!
시라누이 요술, 불덩어리 돌팔매!
Shiranui Magic, Fireball Throwing Stone!
간류 츠바메가에시!
Ganryu Tsubamegaeshi!
누구냐!
Who did that!?
나야!
It's me!
코지로! 이 틈이다! 진나이를 처치해라!
Kojirō! Now! Finish off Jinnai!
아니, 무예가라는 자가 적을 기습해서 쓰러트리는 건 할 수 없다. 정정당당히 승부한다.
No. A martial artist cannot do a surprise attack to take down an enemy. I will have a fair and square match.
고지식한 놈. 케로키치, 스톱.
That guy is too sincere. Stop, Kerokichi.
젠장!
Damn!
자, 덤벼라!
Now, face me!
에잇, 코지로! 네 고지식함이 네 사인이 될지어다! 불덩어리 돌팔매로 불덩어리로 만들어 주겠다!
Kojirō, you fool! Your sincerity will be the cause of your death! I'll make you into a fireball by my Fireball Throwing Stone!
아, 젠장! 물에 젖어서 불덩어리가 안 나와!
Damn! I'm too wet to make a fireball!
지라이얀, 네 칼을 빌려줘라.
Jiraiyan, lend him your sword.
시, 실례를...
E- excuse me...
코지로 놈, 어디까지 선량할 셈이냐. 자, 여기.
That Kojirō guy is way too softhearted. Here you go.
너, 너무한 놈들!
H- how cruel of you guys!
어, 어라?
H- huh?
지, 지라이얀...
J- Jiraiyan...
히미코 씨의 원수, 갚아 주겠소!
I'll have revenge for Ms. Himiko-dasu!
흥.
Hmph.
이건!
What the-!?
뭘 어쩔 생각이오!?
What are you trying to do-dasu!?
사츠마니아를 데려갈 셈이다.
I'm going to take Satsumania with me.
죽어라, 무사시!
Die, Musashi!
무사시! 여긴 우리가 맡을 테니 넌 미사일을 멈춰라!
Musashi! We'll take care of this; you stop that missile!
알겠소!
Understood-dasu!
자, 잡았소!
I got it-dasu!
힘이 세오!
This is strong-dasu!
무사시 군이오?
Is that Musashi-gowasu?
너 거기서 뭐 하고 있는 거야!?
What are you doing over there!?
그런 소리를 해도 미사일이 안 멈춰주오!
Whatever you say, this missile won't stop-dasu!
무사시 님은 목숨을 걸고 미사일을 멈추려고 하고 있습니다.
Mr. Musashi is trying to stop the missile, risking his life.
무사시. 힘내.
Musashi. You can make it.
어째야 좋소, 어째야...
What should I do-dasu? What?
엄마, 저거 뭐야?
Mommy, what's that?
어? 어라, 뭘까?
Huh? I wonder, too!
이대로는 사츠마니아에 명중하고 마오! 어떻게든 미사일의 방향을 바꾸기 위해선...
It will strike Satsumania directly at this rate-dasu! I must change the direction of the missile...
그렇소!
That's it-dasu!
나 머리 좋소!
I'm bright-dasu!
해냈소!
I did it-dasu!
미사일이 돌아온다.
The missile is coming back.
무사시! 여기 오지 마! 절로 가!
Musashi! Don't come to here! Go there!
-미사일이다!
-도망치자, 코지로!
-It's the missile!
-Let's get out of here, Kojirō!
한조! 승부는 나중이다!
Hanzō! We'll finish this later!
그럴 리가!
That's impossible!
이걸로 시라누이 일족의 음모도 쳐부수었군요.
We crushed the conspiracy of Shiranui Clan by this.
저, 사이고 씨, 나, 사이고 씨에게 부탁이 있소만.
Mr. Saigo, I have a request for you-dasu.
무사시 군이 말하고 싶은 것은 알고 있소.
I already know what you want to say-gowasu.
남은 시라누이 일족 말이오.
About the remaining Shiranui Clan...
그거라면 걱정할 것은 없소.
You have nothing to worry about that-gowasu.
저들도 같은 규슈인. 우리도 규슈인.
They are Kyushu people. We are Kyushu people, too.
지금부터는 사이좋게 같이 살아가면 되오.
They can live with us, as friends-gowasu.
사이고 씨, 고맙소!
Mr. Saigo, thank you-dasu!
엄마...
Mother...
이렇게 시라누이 일족의 야망은 사라졌다. 그렇지만 그와 함께 무사시에게 어머니의 면모를 보여 준 히미코도 떠나 버렸다.
And this is how Shiranui Clan's ambition went away.
But with that, Himiko, who gave the feeling of mother to Musashi, went away too.
울지 마라, 무사시. 소년은 어머니의 면모를 버릴 때부터 다시 한번 성장하는 것이다.
Do not cry, Musashi. A boy grows once again when he throws away the feeling of mother.
슬픔을 뛰어넘어 나아가라, 무사시.
Get over the sadness and advance, Musashi.
カラのポケットに　ツキが
飛び込むことも　あるさ
おっきな声で　笑えば
あしたには　朝が来る
無くすものなんか　何もないさ
やっちゃえ！イケイケ！
手ぶらは　強いぜ
てなもんだ　のーてんきに行こう
人生　てなもんさ　チャンスが　ほら
しっぽを振って　追ってくるぜ
てなもんだ　のーてんきに行こう
未来も　てなもんさ　あしたが　ほら
両手ひろげて　笑ってるぜ
코지로를 쓰러트리고 지팡구 제일이 된 나!
I became the number of Jipangu by taking down Kojirō!
생각해보면 기나긴 여정이었소.
It was a long journey-dasu.
코지로 정말 약하오!
Kojirō is so weak-dasu!
아니아니, 내가 강해진 것이오, 분명!
No, no, it must be that I became strong-dasu!
오츠루도 급히 달려와서 미야모토 마을의 모두하고 파티이오!
Otsuru rushed to here with everyone in Miyamoto village, and so we're having a party-dasu!
이걸로 나, 드디어 오츠루하고 결혼할 수 있소!
By this, I can finally marry Otsuru-dasu!
다음 이야기! 코지로에게 이겼소!
Next story! I Defeated Kojirō!
질풍노도의 오츠루이오!
It's stormy Otsuru-dasu!
다음 이야기
코지로에게
이겼소!
기대하세요!
Next Episode
I Defeated
Kojirō!
Look forwards for it!